foreign
[Music]
hey what&#39;s going on guys welcome back to
another video today I&#39;m going to go over
how to set up a video streaming service
in AWS we&#39;ll have a basic react app that
consumes the video we&#39;ll store the video
in S3 and we&#39;re also going to set up a
CDN using cloudfront to sit in front of
our bucket which will improve the
performance
if you&#39;re not familiar with AWS that&#39;s
okay I&#39;m going to go over each Service
as we set it up let&#39;s get started the
first thing we&#39;re going to want to do is
create our S3 bucket if you&#39;re not
familiar with S3 it&#39;s basically just a
file storage service that allows us to
store different files in AWS let&#39;s give
our bucket a name we call it demo video
streaming service
and we can choose a region I&#39;ll do Us
East one we want to make sure ACLS are
disabled and then also that block all
public access is checked because we
don&#39;t want any user out there in the
world to directly access our S3 bucket
we want to limit the traffic to only
come from cloudfront
then we could disable pocket versioning
use the default encryption and just
create our bucket
now that it&#39;s created let&#39;s go ahead and
upload our video
I&#39;m going to select this golf course.mp4
video and then hit upload
now that that&#39;s done uploading we can
try to view the video in our browser so
let&#39;s copy this object URL open up a new
tab and you&#39;ll see that we get this
access denied error and the reason for
that is because we said that this object
cannot be accessed publicly there&#39;s no
read permission here it&#39;s just a dash in
order for our users to view our video
publicly we need to set up our CDN and
before we set that up through cloudfront
I want to go over what a CDN even is
so a CDN stands for Content delivery
Network and that&#39;s really just a
distributed network of servers that
caches content close to end users so
what does that mean well without a CDN
you would just have one origin server in
our case that&#39;s S3 and this will be
responsible for Distributing all the
content to all of our users around the
world so the users in North America will
be pretty close to it but then users in
Australia here will have to wait quite a
bit of time for the content to travel
across the world to them so as you can
see that users that are not very close
to our origin server are going to have
to wait a long time for the video to
load and that&#39;s not going to be a very
good user experience if we set up a CDN
it will allow us to serve our content
through a series of edge locations that
are distributed around the world
and Edge locations are basically just
servers that AWS has across the world
that cache or store our original file
and then serve it to users that are
closer to it so for example the users in
Canada will use this Edge location but
then users in South Africa will use the
edge location closest to them and that&#39;s
going to greatly decrease our load times
because now these users don&#39;t have to
travel all the way to the North America
to get our video content they can just
hit the edge location closest to them
and receive it much faster on top of
that it&#39;s going to save us a ton of
money because the cost of transferring
data from our origin server out into the
world is a lot higher than the cost of
transferring data from an edge location
additionally a CDN is going to help
increase our server&#39;s availability and
uptime because all the requests are
distributed among these Edge locations
if all the requests were only being
handled by one server it could
potentially overload the server and take
it down and lastly a CDN helps prevent
certain attacks like DDOS attacks
because these Edge vocations will be
able to figure out if certain requests
are malicious or if a user is trying to
attack our server and it will then block
that request so to summarize here are
the benefits of a CDN it improves
website load times it reduces bandwidth
costs increases availability and
improves security so let&#39;s go ahead and
set up our CDN in cloudfront
we&#39;re going to go to cloudfront and then
click create distribution for the origin
domain we&#39;re going to select our S3
bucket and this is going to be the
source of our content so where it&#39;s
actually stored
and for the origin access we don&#39;t want
it to be public because our bucket is
private so we&#39;ll select origin access
control settings and this is going to
restrict access to our bucket so that we
can only access it through cloudfront
and we&#39;re going to need to create a
control setting so we can go ahead and
do that
we&#39;ll call it video streaming access
then make sure sign request is checked
and the origin type is S3
so once that that is created you&#39;ll see
that we need to update our S3 bucket and
we&#39;re going to do that right after we
create this distribution
so we could scroll down and then we&#39;ll
one check redirect HTTP to https so that
our connections are secure
and for the cache policy we can just do
caching optimized and that just sets
some default caching Behavior but you&#39;re
free to customize the caching Behavior
if you want
and for the web app firewall I&#39;m not
going to enable it for this tutorial but
in a production environment you would
want to enable this it just enhances
security
for the edge locations I&#39;m just going to
do North America and Europe but in
production you&#39;d probably want to use
all the edge locations
and then we could leave the rest as is
and then let&#39;s create the distribution
now that it&#39;s created let&#39;s go ahead and
copy the policy here and go update our
bucket
so if we click that link it should take
us right to the permissions and then we
could hit edit and the bucket policy
will allow us to Define certain
permissions on objects within the bucket
so if we paste that in we have the
effects set to allow and the principle
is who we&#39;re going to allow access to
and in our case it&#39;s a service called
cloudfront the action we want to allow
them to do is called get object and
that&#39;s just going to allow cloudfront to
read objects within our bucket the
resource defines which objects within
our bucket we want to give them access
to so we have the bucket name and then
slash star and that basically means that
we&#39;re giving access to every object
within our bucket and then lastly we
have a condition and we&#39;re checking if
the AWS Source arm equals this
cloudfront aren&#39;t and this is the
cloudfront distribution we just created
so we could go ahead and save changes
and now we should be able to go back to
our cloudfront distribution
and copy this distribution name
paste that in our browser and then let&#39;s
just grab the key for our video
now we should be able to paste it in and
see our video
and here it is
so last thing we need to do is hook up
our front end to it so I have created a
basic react app with beat and if we open
up the file we just have this app.js and
right below it we&#39;re going to add a
video element
and then we&#39;re going to add some props
to it so we&#39;ll set the width equal to
the height will be 500
then we&#39;ll add controls Loop auto play
and muted
and inside our video element we&#39;re going
to want a source element
and on that we&#39;ll want a source
attribute and we&#39;re going to set that
equal to our video URL here
and then we&#39;ll set the type to video MP4
so now if we hit save we should see that
in our app and here it is
that&#39;s it for this video thank you guys
so much for watching leave a like if you
enjoyed And subscribe if you haven&#39;t
already it would help me out a ton let
me know in the comments if you have any
feedback or what you guys want to see
next and I&#39;ll see you in the next one
[Music]
foreign